<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ATLAS Open Data</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/</link><description>Recent content on ATLAS Open Data</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:51:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of a search for BSM Z' → tt in the single-lepton boosted final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocbsmzptottbar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocbsmzptottbar/</guid><description>Despite the spectacular phenomenological and experimental success of the SM, searches for new physics phenomena at the LHC are constantly ongoing. As an example, with a mass close to the scale of electroweak symmetry breaking, the top quark, besides having a large coupling to the SM Higgs boson, is predicted to have large couplings to new particles hypothesised in many BSM models.
In the following, we focus on implementing the selection criteria of a search for new heavy particles that decay into top-quark pairs in events containing a single charged lepton, large-R jets and missing transverse momentum.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM Higgs boson production in the H → yy decay channel in the two-photon final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtogammagammachannel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtogammagammachannel/</guid><description>The H → yy decay mode provides a very clear and distinctive signature of two isolated and highly energetic photons, and is one of the main channels studied at the LHC. Despite the small branching ratio, a reasonably large signal yield can be obtained thanks to the high photon reconstruction and identification efficiency at the ATLAS experiment. Furthermore, due to the excellent photon energy resolution of the ATLAS calorimeter, the signal manifests itself as a narrow peak in the diphoton invariant mass spectrum on top of a smoothly falling irreducible background from QCD production of two photons.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM Higgs boson production in the H → ZZ decay channel in the four-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtozzfinal4lepchannel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtozzfinal4lepchannel/</guid><description>The search for the SM Higgs boson through the decay H → ZZ → 4l, where l = e or μ, represents the so called &amp;ldquo;golden channel&amp;rdquo; and leads to a narrow four-lepton invariant-mass peak on top a relatively smooth and small background, largely due to the excellent momentum resolution of the ATLAS detector. The Higgs-boson decay branching ratio to the four-lepton final state for the Higgs boson mass of 125 GeV is predicted to be 0.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM Z-boson production in the two-tau-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocztotautaulep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocztotautaulep/</guid><description>The τ-leptons play an important role in the physics programme of the LHC. They serve not only as a foundation to identify and precisely measure several SM production processes such as W → τν and Z → ττ, which represent the main irreducible backgrounds in measurements of the Higgs boson in H → ττ final states, but also are widely used in searches for new physics beyond the SM.
In the following, a selection criteria is made in order to reconstruct the Z → ττ decays from a hadronically decaying τ-lepton, accompanied by a tau-lepton that decays leptonically.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM ZZ diboson production in the four-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoczzprodfinal4lep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoczzprodfinal4lep/</guid><description>The study of ZZ diboson production in pp interactions at the LHC not only can be used as a test of the electroweak sector of the SM. The SM ZZ production can proceed via a SM Higgs boson propagator, although this contribution is suppressed in the region where both Z bosons are produced on-shell. Hence, non-resonant ZZ diboson production is an important background for searches of the SM Higgs boson with its subsequent decay to ZZ.</description></item><item><title>Analysis Framework Introduction</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkintro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkintro/</guid><description>13 TeV ATLAS Open Data analysis frameworks The release of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data, hosted on the CERN Open Data online portal and ATLAS Open Data online portal, is accompanied by a set of analysis frameworks, written in C++ and interfaced with ROOT, Python and RDataFrame, publicly available in a GitHub repository.
The analysis frameworks are aimed to foster educational efforts at the high-school and university levels by providing the material for hands-on physics exercises at different levels of complexity.</description></item><item><title>C++ based framework</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkcpp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkcpp/</guid><description>C++ framework for the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data analysis Introduction The framework makes use of the C++ language and is interfaced with ROOT, and is available under this Github link. After cloning/downloading the repository, the only things you need to setup are: you need to have the ROOT framework (see here for a quick start on ROOT) and a gcc compiler. The current version of the framework was compiled using gcc v6.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of a search for supersymmetric particles in the two-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocsusytwolepfinalstate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocsusytwolepfinalstate/</guid><description>Supersymmetry (SUSY) is one of the most studied extensions of the SM. In its minimal form it predicts new fermionic (bosonic) partners of the fundamental SM bosons (fermions) and an additional Higgs doublet. These new SUSY particles, or &amp;ldquo;sparticles&amp;rdquo;, can provide an elegant solution to the gauge hierarchy problem and provide a natural candidate for dark matter in cases where the lightest supersymmetric particle is a so called weekly interacting massive particle.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM W-boson production in the single-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocwprodfinalsinglelep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocwprodfinalsinglelep/</guid><description>W-bosons are produced abundantly at the LHC and the measurements of the inclusive production cross section of the W bosons and of the asymmetry between the positively-charged and negatively-charged W-boson cross sections constitute important tests of the SM. In addition, W+jets processes are a significant background to studies of SM processes such as single-top production, top-quark pair production, as well as searches for the SM Higgs boson and for BSM physics.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of SM WZ diboson production in the three-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocwzdibosonprod/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocwzdibosonprod/</guid><description>The study of the diboson production is an important part of the physics programme in hadron collisions as it represents an important test of the electroweak sector of the SM. In particular, the WZ diboson production arises from two vector bosons radiated by quarks or from the decay of a virtual W boson into a WZ pair, the latter of which involves a triple gauge coupling.
In order to identify these events, one needs to apply the standard object-selection criteria (defined in &amp;ldquo;Reconstructed physics objects&amp;rdquo;) with a loose lepton pT requirement and tight lepton identification criteria, and an event-selection criteria defined as:</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of t-channel single-top-quark production in the single-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocsingletqprodfinalsinglelep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocsingletqprodfinalsinglelep/</guid><description>At hadron colliders, top quarks are predominantly produced in pairs via the flavour conserving strong interaction, but single top-quark production can occur via charged current electroweak processes involving a Wtb vertex. At leading order (LO) in quantum chromodynamics (QCD) perturbation theory, three sub-processes contribute to single top-quark production: an exchange of a virtual W boson either in the t-channel or in the s-channel, or the associated production of a top quark with an on-shell W boson (Wt).</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of the SM Higgs boson production in the H → WW decay channel in the two-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtowwbosons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdochtowwbosons/</guid><description>As described in the &amp;ldquo;Brief introduction to the Higgs Boson&amp;rdquo;, the H → WW decay branching ratio for the Higgs boson with a mass of 125 GeV is predicted to be 0.214 in the SM, and corresponds to the second-largest branching fraction after the dominant H → bb decay mode. The predicted Higgs-boson production cross sections via the dominant gluon–gluon fusion (ggF) and vector-boson fusion (VBF) times H → WW branching fraction are 10.</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of the SM Z-boson production in the two-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoczprodtwofinallep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoczprodtwofinallep/</guid><description>The study of Z-boson production in pp collisions provides a stringent test of perturbative QCD. In addition, the SM Z-boson process, often produced in association with one or more jets, is a significant background to searches for the SM Higgs boson and for physics beyond the SM.
In order to identify these events, one needs to apply the standard object-selection criteria (defined in &amp;ldquo;Reconstructed physics objects&amp;rdquo;), and leptons are required to pass tight identification criteria, and an event-selection criteria defined as:</description></item><item><title>Example of physics analysis: the case of the top-quark pair production in the single-lepton final state</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoctopquarkpairprodfinalsinglelep/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoctopquarkpairprodfinalsinglelep/</guid><description>The top quark is the heaviest elementary particle in the SM, with a mass mt of around 172.5 GeV, which is close to the electroweak symmetry breaking scale. At the LHC, top quarks are primarily produced in quark–antiquark pairs (tt), and due to its large production cross section ( around 830 pb at 13 TeV), the LHC can be viewed as &amp;ldquo;a top-quark factory&amp;rdquo;. Top quarks have a rich phenomenology which includes high-pT jets, b-jets, leptons and missing transverse momentum.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocglossary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocglossary/</guid><description>Glossary Below a few ATLAS physics terms are explained. This is not intended to be an exhaustive glossary, more detailed answers might be found using the search engine located in the upper right corner of this page or at the official ATLAS Collaboration and CERN websites.
Detector layout The ATLAS detector has a layout that is typical for a collider detector. There are two types of detector components: tracking detectors, which measure the position of a crossing charged particle with minimal disturbance, and calorimeters, which measure the energy of a particle by total absorption.</description></item><item><title>Physics Analysis Examples</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisexamples/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisexamples/</guid><description>The general aim of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data and tools released is to provide a straightforward interface to replicate the procedures used by high-energy-physics researchers and enable users to experience the analysis of particle physics data in educational environments. Therefore, it is of significant interest to check the correct modelling of several SM process by the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data MC simulation.
Hence, twelve examples of physics analysis (as reported in official release document ATL-OREACH-PUB-2020-001) using the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data inspired by and following as closely as possible the procedures and selections taken in already published ATLAS Collaboration physics results are introduced:</description></item><item><title>PyROOT framework</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkpyroot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkpyroot/</guid><description>PyROOT framework for the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data analysis Introduction The framework makes use of the Python language and is interfaced with ROOT, and is available under this Github link. After cloning/downloading the repository, the only thing you need to have is Python installed. The master version of this framework uses python3. The python2 branch uses python2.
The 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data are hosted on the CERN Open Data portal and ATLAS Open Data portal in this documentation.</description></item><item><title>Python uproot framework</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkpython/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkpython/</guid><description>Python uproot framework About This is an analysis code that may be used to analyse the data of the ATLAS published dataset, and is available at this Github link
This framework uses Python uproot and pandas/numpy to have no dependency on ROOT. This framework uses python3.
The 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data are hosted on the CERN Open Data portal and ATLAS Open Data portal in this documentation. The framework can access the samples in two ways:</description></item><item><title>RData framework</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkrdata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocanalysisframeworkrdata/</guid><description>RDataFrame framework for the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data analysis Coming very soon!
Navigation Jump back to the previous framework or jump back to the summary page for the analysis frameworks or the general summary page.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/about/</guid><description>Aims of this Open Access project</description></item><item><title>13TeV Doc</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocoverview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocoverview/</guid><description>The ATLAS Open Data 13 TeV docs The aim of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data is to provide data and tools to high school, undergraduate and graduate students, as well as teachers and lecturers, to help educate and train them in analysis techniques used in experimental particle physics. Sharing data collected by the ATLAS experiment aims to generate excitement and enthusiasm for fundamental research, inspiring physicists of the future.</description></item><item><title>8TeV Analyses</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocanalyses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocanalyses/</guid><description>Analyses We have prepared seven analyses for you. Ranging from measuring Standard Model particles including a Higgs analysis and a search for a Beyond the Standard Model particle. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at these processes.
\( W \) Boson Analysis The \( W \) and \( Z \) bosons are together known as the weak or the intermediate vector bosons. These Standard Model elementary particles mediate the weak interaction.
The \( W \) boson analysis is intended to provide an example for a high statistics analysis using the ATLAS open data dataset.</description></item><item><title>8TeV Doc</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocoverview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocoverview/</guid><description>Welcome to ATLAS at the LHC.
We have prepared some data for you. Come and take a look.
It is ready for you to use, just for curiosity, as a teaching tool or to dive in and write your own analysis code.
This section is aimed at University students and post graduate researchers. Software skills may help, but are not essential. A good amount of motivation is the main requirement to follow the various steps.</description></item><item><title>A Week At Cern</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/blogpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/blogpost/</guid><description>Our one week internship at CERN</description></item><item><title>App @13 TeV</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/histogram-analyser-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/histogram-analyser-02/</guid><description>Histogram Analyser only simulated data @13 TeV</description></item><item><title>App @13 TeV</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/histogram-analyser-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/histogram-analyser-03/</guid><description>Histogram Analyser simulated and real data @13 TeV</description></item><item><title>Apps</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/apps/</guid><description>All Apps: Online and Electron</description></item><item><title>ATLAS events</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocevents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocevents/</guid><description>ATLAS events Beams of protons are accelerated around the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) and are brought to collide at the centre of the ATLAS detector. The collisions produce debris in the form of new particles which fly out in all directions. Over a billion particle interactions take place in the ATLAS detector every second.
The protons within the two beams are grouped in bunches which are squeezed down in size to increase the chances of a collision.</description></item><item><title>Create a new plot</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocnewplot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocnewplot/</guid><description>Create a new plot You can create some new plots, but you need to run over all the datasets.
If you are running the small VM, you need to transfer the complete dataset you have downloaded into your input directory.
python DownloadScript.py -a 'unzip, replace' This command unzips complete_set_of_ATLAS_open_data_samples_July_2016.zip and replaces the data samples that are currently in your input directory.
Now you have all the data, it could take a long time to produce plots.</description></item><item><title>Data</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/data/</guid><description>The first page to drive the users to the data samples and resources</description></item><item><title>Data and simulated data</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocdata/</guid><description>Data and simulated data Data The ATLAS collaboration has released 1 inverse femtobarn of data. The ATLAS Open Data datasets are available on this website and on the CERN Open Data portal.
One inverse femtobarn corresponds to approximately 100 trillion proton-proton collisions.
Simulated data Simulated data, commonly named Monte Carlo (MC), are a key feature for the LHC experiments. These events are simulated using current theoretical models and are used to compare theory with real data.</description></item><item><title>Dataset details</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocdatadetails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocdatadetails/</guid><description>Dataset Details An important aspect of the data samples is that they were prepared specifically for educational purposes. To this end, precision has been traded for simplicity of use. The introduced simplifications are:
No facilities to estimate systematic uncertainties have been included as these quickly introduce large complexities.
The b-tagging scale factor is computed for a specific working point (MV1@70% efficiency). The user, however, is free to specify the b-tagging weight used for tagging jets allowing for a potential mismatch of the definition considered in the scale factor calculation and the one being actually applied.</description></item><item><title>Detector App</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/detector-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/detector-app/</guid><description>A ROOTJS visualisation of the ATLAS detector</description></item><item><title>Event selection</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoceventsel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoceventsel/</guid><description>Event selection The events in the dataset ntuples have been selected according to a selection criteria. The variables are defined in variable names.
The standard event based selection criteria are:
A single electron or muon trigger has fired; The primary vertex has at least 5 tracks; There is at least one good lepton with \( p_T \) &amp;gt; 25 GeV; Leptons are required to be isolated ( Both ptcone30 and etcone20 &amp;lt; 0.</description></item><item><title>Glossary</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocglossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocglossary/</guid><description>Glossary This is not intended to be an exhaustive glossary. You will find answers to many of your questions by using a search engine. However, here are a few ATLAS physics terms explained to start you off.
ATLAS coordinate system The coordinate system of ATLAS is a right-handed coordinate system with the x-axis pointing towards the centre of the LHC tunnel, and the z-axis along the tunnel. The y-axis is slightly tilted with respect to vertical due to the general tilt of the tunnel.</description></item><item><title>Histogram animation</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdochistoanimation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdochistoanimation/</guid><description>Histogram animation An animation of the accumulation of Higgs events over time in the four-lepton channel show us that it is important to collect large data samples. You can see the signal emerging from the background as more and more events are added.
As more data is collected (notice the date changing), the number of events analysed increases (notice the change in scale of the y-axis). The size of the error bars on the data points decrease as the volume of data increases, allowing the signal to be seen.</description></item><item><title>Install Ubuntu</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocinstallubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocinstallubuntu/</guid><description>Ubuntu Create a virtual machine containing Ubuntu — Click the &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; button.
— In the settings window specify the &amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; (in the future you can change), the &amp;ldquo;Type&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Version&amp;rdquo; of the operating system and click &amp;ldquo;Next&amp;rdquo;. For example - Name: My_Ubuntu (o_0), Type: Linux, Version: Ubuntu (64-bit).
— The machine claims that the minimum memory size (RAM) requirements for full-fledged work Linux,, 1024MB. But if you want your machine to work well, then select the volume for more depending on the RAM of your computer (2 GB if RAM of your computer 8 GB) and click &amp;ldquo;Next&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocintroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocintroduction/</guid><description>The Large Hadron Collider The main objective in a particle physics experiment is, often, to produce new particles by carrying out collisions. The choice of beam particle is governed by the particular objectives of the experiment. The particles that constitute the beam must be stable, and it should be possible to produce and accelerate them in large numbers. Hence the most obvious choices are electrons, positrons, protons and anti-protons. The lower energy loss from synchrotron radiation is the main argument in favour of a hadron collider when a greater energy reach is the primary motivation, as is the case of the Large Hadron Collider (LHC).</description></item><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocjupyternotebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocjupyternotebooks/</guid><description>13 TeV ATLAS Open Data Jupyter Notebooks The release of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data is accompanied by a set of Jupyter notebooks that allow data analysis to be performed directly in a web browser by integrating the ROOT framework with the Jupyter notebook technology, a combination called &amp;ldquo;ROOTbook&amp;rdquo;. Also, multiple ROOT-independent examples are in place.
Several notebooks with analysis examples and an interface to launch the framework mentioned above, are available using SWAN (Service for Web based ANalysis) and Binder executable platforms.</description></item><item><title>More plots</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocmoreplots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocmoreplots/</guid><description>More plots \( Z \) Analysis The transverse mass of the \( Z \) candidate shows a peak in the distribution in the 90-95 GeV bin. The average \( Z \) mass based on published results is 91.1876 +/- 0.0021 GeV. The real and simulated data distributions are in good agreement.
If we add up the number of events in this distribution we see we have about 500 \( Z \) candidates.</description></item><item><title>News/Blog</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/news/</guid><description>Updates from the ATLAS Open Data community</description></item><item><title>Plots explained</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocplots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocplots/</guid><description>Plots explained After running the TTbarAnalysis and plotting the results you will have lots of plots in your Output directory.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at a few plots.
The primary vertex position in the coordinate z (where the z axis follows the beam direction and positive z points towards Geneva) is centered around zero. This is expected since the origin of the coordinate system is the nominal interaction point.</description></item><item><title>SaaS</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/saas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/saas/</guid><description>Recipes for infrastructure deployment</description></item><item><title>Set up your environment</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocsetupenv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocsetupenv/</guid><description>Setup Your Environment Watch the video &amp;lsquo;Setup your environment&amp;rsquo; to give you an idea what you will have to do.
We have provided the datasets and software in a variety of formats. You choose how you want to use them:
If you want to have a quick look at the data, not investing too much time, you can use the small virtual machine (06-Feb-2017), which contains 10% of the data.</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/software/</guid><description>All Soft Tools</description></item><item><title>Take a closer look</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoccloserlook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoccloserlook/</guid><description>Take a closer look The first thing to say is that you cannot break it !
Change the code, do whatever you like.
You have a local copy. If for some reason it all goes horribly wrong, just delete what you have and start again.
No-one will know. No-one will care.
It is much better to work out things for yourself. Go on, make a change to the code and see if it does what you intend.</description></item><item><title>Take a closer look at the data</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoccloserlookdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdoccloserlookdata/</guid><description>Take a look at the data Watch the video &amp;lsquo;Take a look at the data&amp;rsquo; to give you an idea what you need to do.
In your terminal window, you are in the main directory ATLAS-DataAndTools. Here you can two python scripts RunScript.py and PlotResults.py. These are the two key scripts you need to run an analysis.
You will see there are 6 folders:
Analysis: Code for 7 analyses have been prepared for you.</description></item><item><title>Variable names</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocvarnames/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/8tevdocvarnames/</guid><description>Variable names Here are the definitions of the variable names as used in the analysis code and in the ntuples.
variable name ntuple branchname type description runNumber runNumber int run identifier eventNumber eventNumber int event identifier channelNumber int Data sample ID eg WW sample 105985 mcWeight mcWeight float weight of a simulated event pvxp_n pvxp_n int number of primary vertices vxp_z vxp_z float z-position of the primary vertex SF_PILEUP scaleFactor_PILEUP float scalefactor for pileup reweighting.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Machines</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocvirtualmachines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdocvirtualmachines/</guid><description>13 TeV ATLAS Open Data virtual machine The 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data virtual machine (VM) allows you to create a virtual (rather than actual) operating system and test the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data on your own host machine.
First, you will find below the instruction of how to install the Oracle VirtualBox, and after that the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data virtual machine.
Follow the video tutorials in our CDS collection here</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/resources/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/resources/</guid><description>A detailed summary of the resources</description></item><item><title>A Public Dataset For Teaching Jet Reconstruction</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-custom/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-custom/</guid><description>Others datasets &amp;amp; collections</description></item><item><title>The 8 TeV ...</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-8tev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-8tev/</guid><description>The 8 TeV datasets from 2016</description></item><item><title>Visites</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/tours/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/tours/</guid><description>Un regard guidé sur toutes les ressources et docs</description></item><item><title>The 13 TeV ...</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-13tev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 21:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/samples-13tev/</guid><description>The 13 TeV datasets from 2020</description></item></channel></rss>