<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ATLAS Open Data</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/</link><description>Recent content on ATLAS Open Data</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>13 TeV Doc</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevoverview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevoverview/</guid><description>A new set of pp collision data has been released by the ATLAS Collaboration to the public for educational purposes. The data has been collected by the ATLAS detector at the LHC at 13 TeV during the year 2016 and corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 10 fb-1. The pp collision data is accompanied by a set of MC simulated samples describing several processes which are used to model the expected distributions of different signal and background events.</description></item><item><title>13 TeV List of Branches and Variables</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevlistbranches/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevlistbranches/</guid><description>Description of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data branches and variables The full list of ROOT branches and variables contained within the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data is presented below:
Navigation Go to the next section or jump back to the summary page.</description></item><item><title>13 TeV Physics Analysis Examples</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevphysicsanalysisexamples/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevphysicsanalysisexamples/</guid><description>13 TeV ATLAS Open Data physics analysis examples The general aim of the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data and tools released is to provide a straightforward interface to replicate the procedures used by high-energy-physics researchers and enable users to experience the analysis of particle physics data in educational environments. Therefore, it is of significant interest to check the correct modelling of several SM process by the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data MC simulation.</description></item><item><title>Available Physics Objects 13 TeV</title><link>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevavailphysobj/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 04:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-open-data-docs.github.io/WoW/13tevdoc/13tevavailphysobj/</guid><description>Reconstructed physics objects within the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data Several reconstructed physics objects (electrons, muons, photons, hadronically decaying tau-leptons, small-R jets, large-R jets) are contained within the 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data, and their preselection requirements are detailed below:
The 13 TeV ATLAS Open Data events are selected by applying several event-quality and trigger criteria, and classified according to the type and multiplicity of reconstructed objects with high transverse momentum.</description></item></channel></rss>